<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Thom Shutt</title>
    <link>http://thomshutt.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Thom Shutt</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2015 12:59:43 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://thomshutt.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Kindle Fire HD 7 - Two Months In</title>
      <link>http://thomshutt.github.io/post/kindlefire/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2015 12:59:43 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://thomshutt.github.io/post/kindlefire/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I bought a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gsmarena.com/amazon_fire_hd_7-6689.php&#34;&gt;Kindle Fire HD 7&lt;/a&gt; for around £50 during Amazon&amp;rsquo;s recent &amp;lsquo;Prime Day&amp;rsquo; sale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s now been supplanted by Amazon&amp;rsquo;s low-cost &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.co.uk/gp/product/B00Y3TM6CO&#34;&gt;Fire&lt;/a&gt; offering, which seems to be largely the same device (albeit with a slightly lower resolution), so most of this post probably holds true for that device too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;why:7272601f3bafbed2ae37022f5ad8c58c&#34;&gt;Why?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The device was supposed to be a half-way point between my Kindle and laptop - something portable that would allow me to read PDFs of things that don&amp;rsquo;t convert well to e-book format (Programming book / books in Farsi / anything that&amp;rsquo;s been badly scanned), without the distractions of something that&amp;rsquo;s connected to the internet and full of other distractions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;and:7272601f3bafbed2ae37022f5ad8c58c&#34;&gt;And?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, things have worked out surprisingly well. I&amp;rsquo;ve managed to resist the temptation to install any apps on there or to use the web browser much. Keeping it permanently in Aeroplane mode has meant that there&amp;rsquo;s just enough overhead to doing something online that I&amp;rsquo;ll switch to my laptop if needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The built-in PDF reader is basic but works well for my needs (reading a book one page at a time, cover-to-cover). It allows skipping to different page numbers, but no e.g table-of-contents functionality:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://thomshutt.github.io/images/kindle/Kindle1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;pure-img&#34; &gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been loading documents on via USB, being on OSX means that I have to use the Android file transfer app (rather than the tablet presenting itself as a block USB device), which is mildy annoying but not too much of a pain. It also seems to be very fussy about where things are placed - everything needs to go in &lt;em&gt;documents/&lt;/em&gt; and trying to organise books via subfolders (e.g &lt;em&gt;documents/computing/&lt;/em&gt;) causes them to be ignored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One minor-but-actually-quite-annoying thing is that PDF covers aren&amp;rsquo;t picked up for side-loaded documents, meaning that my UI has ended up being full of default covers (see below). This seems to have been an issue since &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/forum/kindle?_encoding=UTF8&amp;amp;cdForum=Fx1D7SY3BVSESG&amp;amp;cdThread=TxM9YB62T1DLCN&#34;&gt;2011&lt;/a&gt; and seems like a weird one to not have fixed. The only reason I can think of is that Amazon really don&amp;rsquo;t expect/want the device to be used in this way - Fire OS seems very much to be designed as a slick content consumption experience, provided that you buy in fully to the Amazon ecosystem (Prime Video, Photo Storage etc.):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://thomshutt.github.io/images/kindle/Kindle2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; class=&#34;pure-img&#34; &gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Battery life has been better than I expected - I haven&amp;rsquo;t done any scientific testing, but I generally get a few days of solid reading (3-4 hours per day) before I need to dig out the charger. It also charges very quickly, but needs the provided charger (all of my other microUSB chargers were deemed to be too low-power by it).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anecdotally, I finding it less straining on my eyes than my laptop, but more so than my Kindle (which is what I&amp;rsquo;d expect). Combined with the lack of other distractions on there, this makes it usually possible to read on there at night without affecting my ability to go to sleep.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;tl-dr:7272601f3bafbed2ae37022f5ad8c58c&#34;&gt;TL;DR?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, I&amp;rsquo;d definitely recommend the Fire HD 7 (or the new Fire tablet) with the caveat that I&amp;rsquo;m recommending it for my exact use case. For less than £50, I&amp;rsquo;ve been able to do a lot more distraction-free reading that I would have on my laptop.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>